Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955. George Lynes Platt photographs, 1935-1953 (MS Thr 483): Guide.
George Lynes Platt photographs,
- Richter, Ray., (Box 5)
  Head shot, lying on carpet, facing right, shirtless, head fills the bottom half of photo.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,840.
- Roy, Pierre., (Box 5)
  Seated at table, facing left, his left arm resting on table slightly behind a paper chain, holding a baseball; tear, approximately 1" long, on right edge.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,841.
- Russell, Bertrand., (Box 4)
  Smoking a pipe.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,607.
  Number on photograph: 577-2.
- Ryan, Mrs. Alan, Jr.., (Box 5)
  Bust-length in center of frame, wearing cap-sleeved blouse and white gloves, looking right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,842.
- Santoro, Joe., (Box 5)
  Headshot, shirtless, looking left.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,843.
- Sharaff, Irene., (Box 5)
  HTC No.: HTC 22,656.
  [no photo in folder]
- Sharaff, Irene., (Box 5)
  With cello and cigarette.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,608.
  Number on photograph: LH 288 9-5.
- Sharaff, Irene., (Box 5)
  Seated, looking up; orange damage spots.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,609.
  Location: Box 4 of 5.
- Sharaff, Irene., (Box 5)
  Seated, looking front.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,610.
  Number on photograph: LH 288 9-7.
- Sharaff, Irene., (Box 5)
  Seated, looking down.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,611.
- Sitwell, Edith., (Box 5)
  Leaning against bridge, facing right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,638.
  Number on photograph: 526-B.
- Sitwell, Edith., (Box 5)
  Seated, wearing heavily draped brocade and large cuff bracelets, looking front with left hand raised, palm out.
  HTC No.: HTC 22,661.
- Sitwell, Osbert, 1953., (Box 5)
  Seated on couch with elbows resting on the back of couch; facing front, looking left.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,879.
- Sitwell, Osbert, 1953., (Box 5)
  Seated in armchair in living room, facing and looking right, his right hand supporting chin.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,880.
- Sitwell, Osbert., (Box 5)
  Leaning against window on left side of frame.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,639.
  Number on photograph: 199-6.
- Starkowski, Ted, 1951., (Box 4)
  Nude man lying flat on back with arms raised above head on left side of photograph; textured appearance.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,710.
- Starkowski, Ted., (Box 4)
  Standing, his left hand in pocket and his right hand holding a triangle, looking up left.
  Note on folder: "This is really Paul Cadmus - enczafran(?) Dec 18 '03."
  HTC No.: HTC 20,844.
- Stein, Gertrude., (Box 4)
  Headshot, viewed from the elbows up, facing forwards and looking slightly right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,845.
- Stein, Gertrude., (Box 4)
  View of face, right profile, river and trees in background.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,846.
- Stein, Gertrude., (Box 4)
  View from elbows up, looking right, river and trees in background.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,847.
- Steinberg, Saul., (Box 4)
  Profile of Steinberg facing left in front of drawing of man riding horse.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,715.
- Stravinsky, Igor., (Box 4)
  Sitting on porch, his left leg crossed over his right leg, looking forward and up.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,848.
- Stravinsky, Igor., (Box 4)
  Standing on porch, leaning on pole to his left, hands in pockets, looking slightly right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,849.
- Stravinsky, Igor., (Box 4)
  Sitting on porch, his left leg crossed over his right leg, looking forward.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,965.
- Stravinsky, Igor;; Auden, W. H., (Box 5)
  Contact sheet; various poses on porch with numerous botanicals.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,693.
- Studio Wall, 1952., (Box 5)
  Undersized photograph (approximately 6-1/4 by 5-3/8"); Christmas card; George Platt Lynes studio wall, c. 1952, painted for background by Bernard Perlin; back reads "with love Une Geo."
  HTC No.: HTC 20,878.
- Studio Wall, (Box 6)
  Undersize photograph of heavily graffitied studio wall.
- Tanguy, Yves., (Box 5)
  View from elbows up which occupies bottom half of photograph; left half of face is blurred out; face appears between two fire-like images which appear to be photo special effects.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,850.
- Tanguy, Yves., (Box 5)
  View from elbows up which occupies whole of photograph; left quarter of face is blurred out.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,851.
- Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1898-1957., (Box 5)
  In studio, painting.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,852.
- Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1898-1957., (Box 5)
  At work on a portrait of George Platt Lynes, painting, visible on left half of photograph, facing left; gelatin silver print 24 x 19 cm;.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,959.
  Number on photograph: A.
- Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1898-1957., (Box 5)
  Seated against partial wall, bones on top of wall, looking left.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,716.
  Number on photograph: 990 A.
- Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1898-1957., (Box 5)
  Seated with right arm on arm of chair. Dressed in dotted dressing gown? Looking slightly left.
  HTC No.: HTC 22,649.
  Numbers on photograph: p 46-47.
- Tichenor, George., (Box 5)
  In military uniform; view of Tichenor from the elbows up occupies bottom right quadrant of photo; the rest of the space is occupied by a cage-like structure.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,853.
- Tichenor, George;; Magellanes, Nicholas; unidentified man, 1940., (Box 5)
  Tichenor standing in front of platform, arms crossed, facing camera; Magellanes and unidentified man on either side of platform, each with chin resting in his hands, facing each other, Magellanes on right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,945.
- Tichenor, Jonathan., (Box 5)
  Facing back and looking right, arms crossed, wearing sleeveless undershirt, view from hips up.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,854.
- Tooker, George., (Box 5)
  Seated, leaning slightly back, wearing white undershirt and shorts, holding cigarette in his right hand, looking forward.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,855.
- Tooker, George., (Box 5)
  View from the hips up, leaning against wall, arms crossed, wearing white undershirt, looking down and right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,856.
- Toumanova, Tamara, 1941., (Box 5)
  Facing front with driftwood.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,616.
- Toumanova, Tamara, 1938., (Box 5)
  Leaning against wall in white dress.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,618.
  Number on photograph: B.
- Toumanova, Tamara, 1938., (Box 5)
  Standing, looking down and left, wearing triangular hat, holding a corner of her apron out to her left with her right hand, her right hand at her waist with palm facing upwards.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,967.
- Unidentified., (Box 6)
  Bald man in overcoat, viewed from the elbows up, seated, looking right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,890.
  Number on photograph: 585 A.
- Unidentified., (Box 6)
  Man and woman viewed from waist up, both facing right, man holding a small tray with leaves in it.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,903.
- Unidentified, 1947., (Box 6)
  Man wearing white sweatshirt and jeans, standing against white wall, hands in pockets, viewed full front.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,905.
- Unidentified, 1947., (Box 6)
  Man wearing white sweatshirt and jeans, standing against white wall, wooden scaffolding obscuring the view.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,906.
- Unidentified, 1940., (Box 6)
  Young girl (approx. age 10) standing behind white chair, looking right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,910.
- Unidentified, 1940., (Box 6)
  Young girl (approx. age 10) seated, her chin on her hands, facing camera.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,911.
- Unidentified, 1938., (Box 6)
  Mother and child, both nude; mother facing back, seated on knees; child on her shoulders, facing left. Photo by J. Russell Lynes (J.R. Lynes, Shipley School, Bryn Mawr, Penn.), Rolleiflex 6x6, on Agfa Superpan Press.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,915.
- Unidentified., (Box 6)
  Shirtless man reclining on grass, striped shirt tied around his neck, smiling; book, sunglasses, and container of film in foreground.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,918.
- Unidentified., (Box 6)
  Shirtless man leaning against tree, striped shirt tied around his neck, hands behind back, looking right; grassy park in background.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,919.
- Unidentified., (Box 6)
  Leaning against carpet roll, his chin in his right hand, facing front.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,934.
- Unidentified., (Box 6)
  Straddling carpet roll, hands on knees, facing front, smiling.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,935.
- Unidentified. Los Angeles, 1947., (Box 6)
  In profile, facing left, face obscured, shirtless, holding on to window frame with right hand, hill with houses in background.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,938.
- Unidentified. Los Angeles, 1947., (Box 6)
  Two black bars divide photograph horizontally into thirds; in top third, head visible, looking up left with mouth open. In bottom two thirds, body and shadow of body visible in sillhouette, but details obscured.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,939.
- Unidentified. 1940., (Box 6)
  Standing in field, looking up and shading eyes with his right hand; shirtless, holding shirt over his left arm.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,944.
- Unidentified Man., (Box 6)
  Shirtless man kneeling at bedside, hands folded on bed and head resting between arms with eyes closed.
- Unidentified Man., (Box 6)
  Man in white T-shirt seated before shutter-paneled folding doors. Arms folded across chest, looking front.
  HTC No.: HTC 22, 633.
- Unidentified Man., (Box 6)
  Mounted, undersized print; young man, shirtless and seated before angled mirrors, looking up and forward.
  HTC No.: HTC 22, 665.
- Unidentified Man. 5 prints., (Box 6)
  1. Man in calf-length white tights leaning with his left elbow on pole (barre?), facing left.
  2. Close-up on man in tights' buttocks and thighs.
  3. Man in tights from behind, leaning with both arms stretched along pole and right ankle crossed over left.
  4. Man in tights seated, looking right, with left knee up.
  5. Man in tights' torso and thighs form an 'L' on Left and bottom of photograph.
  HTC No.: HTC 22,671.
- Unidentified Man., (Box 6)
  Man in gingham boxer shorts kneeling in patterned-fabric, with hands held behind back, looking up.
  HTC No.: HTC 22, 672.
- Unidentified Man., (Box 6)
  Neck, torso, and pelvis of a nude man; grainy quality.
  HTC No.: HTC 22, 673.
- Valdez, Tito., (Box 5)
  Undersized photo (approximately 8-3/4 by 6-1/2"); man dressed in cape, embroidered vest, loose pants, and cap with hands on hips, looking forward.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,857.
- Valdez, Tito., (Box 5)
  Undersized photo (approximately 8-3/4 by 6-1/2"); man dressed in cape, loose pants, and cap with arms spread wide to fan out cape, looking forward and up.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,858.
- Valdez, Tito., (Box 5)
  Man dressed in cape, embroidered vest, loose pants, and cap with his right arm extended to spread out the cape; looking up left; back reads "dancer of the Casino de Paris, Paris."
  HTC No.: HTC 20,859.
- Vreeland, Diana., (Box 5)
  Seated on couch in living room, holding small dog, smiling at camera.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,860.
- Vreeland, Diana., (Box 5)
  Seated on windowsill in living room with feet on couch, legs crossed, looking down right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,861.
- Waugh, Evelyn., (Box 5)
  Seated in study with his right elbow on table, body angled right, smoking cigar.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,717.
  Number on photograph: LA 145 G-10.
- Waugh, Evelyn., (Box 5)
  Seated in study with arms crossed on desk, smoking cigar.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,718.
  Number on photograph: LA 145 G-14.
- Waugh, Evelyn., (Box 5)
  Body facing forward, his left elbow on desk and his left hand holding a cigar to his lips.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,862.
  Number on photograph: OA23506.
- Wescott, Barbara., (Box 5)
  Seated on filigree couch, facing front, wearing dress with lace collar.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,719.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated on desk, hands clasped, facing forward.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,721.
  Number on photograph: 367-5.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated on desk, hands clasped, looking left.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,722.
  Number on photograph: 367-6.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated on chair, his left arm resting on desk, smiling.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,723.
  Number on photograph: 367-8.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated on chair, his left arm resting on desk, leaning forward in chair, his right hand clenched in his lap.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,724.
  Number on photograph: 367-14.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated, looking forward, hands clasped in lap, almost identical to HTC 20-726 except that hands are slightly more shadowed and definition is less precise.
  Number on photograph: 370-30.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated, looking forward, hands clasped in lap, almost identical to HTC 20-725 except that hands are slightly less shadowed and definition is more precise.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,726.
  Number on photograph: 370-22.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated, looking right, his right eye slightly narrowed as if incredulous.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,727.
  Number on photograph: 370-28.
- Wescott, Glenway., (Box 5)
  Seated, looking right, both eyes wide open as if alert.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,728.
- Wescott, Glenway, 1930., (Box 5)
  Undersized photograph (approximately 5 by 8"); appears to be photograph of proof; Wescott lying on white towel and wrapped in white terrycloth bathrobe, looking right, viewed from the shoulders up.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,884.
  Number on photograph: 97.
- Wescott, Glenway, 1930., (Box 5)
  Undersized photograph (approximately 5 by 8"); appears to be photograph of proof; Wescott reclining on bed, propped against pillows, facing and looking right, his right hand on chin.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,885.
  Number on photograph: 981.
- Wescott, Glenway, 1940., (Box 5)
  Undersized photograph (approximately 7.5" square); Wescott seated at desk looking at newspaper, holding cigarette to mouth with his left hand; at Stone-Blossom; Paul Cadmus drawing of Glenway Wecott in background.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,898.
- Wescott, Glenway, 1950., (Box 5)
  Wescott standing outdoors, leaning against dead tree; meadow and male nude in background.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,899.
- Wescott, Glenway;; Lynes, George Platt (?), Mulhocaway River, N.J., 1940., (Box 5)
  Both nude in river, near small waterfall, Wescott standing facing camera, Lynes seated facing back, trees and grasses in background.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,909.
- Wescott, Lloyd, 1940., (Box 5)
  Shirtless man with goatee viewed from the waist up, arms slightly spread out, looking right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,886.
  Number on photograph: 16-O.
- Wescott, Lloyd, 1933., (Box 5)
  Wearing black T-shirt and black pants, facing front, arms spread out; leaning against some sort of industrial wall.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,917.
- Wescott, Lloyd, 1940., (Box 5)
  Undersized photograph (approx. 7 11/16" by 7 10/16"); in doorway, holding cigarette in his right hand, looking left.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,924.
- Wescott, Lloyd, 1940., (Box 5)
  View from shoulders up, standing by barn door, facing camera, smiling.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,925.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 28.
- Wescott, Lloyd, 1940., (Box 5)
  Seated on a hay bale, looking front.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,926.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 26.
- Wescott, Lloyd, 1940., (Box 5)
  Seated on a hay bale, looking right.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,927.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 27.
- Wescott, Lloyd;; Wescott, Barbara Harrison,1940., (Box 5)
  With cows, crouched down near barn floor, he behind her.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,928.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 10.
- Wescott, Lloyd;; Wescott, Barbara Harrison,1940., (Box 5)
  Seated on haystack, in profile, he behind her with his hands on her shoulders, both smiling.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,929.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 3.
- Wescott, Lloyd;; Wescott, Barbara Harrison, 1940., (Box 5)
  Standing with barn door in background, facing each other, her arm on his shoulder.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,930.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 21.
- Wescott, Lloyd;; Wescott, Barbara Harrison, 1940., (Box 5)
  Seated with barn door in background, facing right, she holding a cigarette.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,931.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 13.
- Wescott, Lloyd;; Wescott, Barbara Harrison, 1940., (Box 5)
  He standing by barn door, looking down; she in profile at bottom left, looking left.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,932.
  Number on photograph: 14328 LA 18.
- Westcott, Glenway and Bocquillion., (Box 5)
  One man, standing and facing back, lighting a kneeling man's cigarette.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,708.
- Westcott, Glenway and Bocquillion., (Box 5)
  One man standing, facing back with arms crossed; another man kneeling, his left hand holding a hankerchief to his face and his right hand holding a cigarette.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,709.
- Wheeler, Monroe., (Box 5)
  Leaning against wall with thumbs under pants waistline.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,863.
  Number on photograph: 294-20.
- Wheeler, Monroe., (Box 5)
  Standing in corridor with hands in pockets, smiling ahead at camera.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,864.
  Number on photograph: 294-18.
- Whitney, Betsey., (Box 5)
  Seated with face resting on her left hand, looking left.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,720.
- Williams, Mona., (Box 5)
  Seated on filigree couch, looking right, small dog in her lap.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,729.
- Williams, Tennessee.
  See caption on photo.
  HTC No.: (unknown)
- Windham, Donald., (Box 5)
  Two men in sailor suits, with driftwood, looking at each other.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,730.
- Windham, Donald., (Box 5)
  Man in sailor suit, with driftwood, looking forward.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,731.
- Windham, Donald., (Box 5)
  Seated on floor, his right leg propped up, his right arm holding his jacket over his shoulder, his shadow visible on the wall behind him.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,865.
- Windham, Donald., (Box 5)
  View from the elbows up which occupies bottom 2/3 of photo; looking right and slightly up; back reads "Donald Windham 23/ 5 St Luke Place/ Ph. 3-6188."
  HTC No.: HTC 20,866.
- Wisner, John., (Box 5)
  Shirtless, leaning against back of chair; handwritten X in lower right-hand corner.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,695.
- Wisner, John (?)., (Box 5)
  Contact sheet: 16 proofs taken under a tree.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,615.
  Number on photograph: 2.
- Yeon, John., (Box 5)
  In hammock, looking forward, A. Jenson Yow (ex Morgan Library Conservator).
  HTC No.: HTC 20,732.
- Ynocencio, A. J.., (Box 5)
  Nude man, seated and looking back left, with his right arm on his right thigh.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,712.
- Zadkine, Ossip., (Box 5)
  In studio, chiseling at relief.
  HTC No.: HTC 20,867.